FARKHAN HAMZAH FIRDAUS

PBondowoso, East Java, Indonesia ■ farhanhamzah71@gmail.com ☐ +6281249803846

https://www.linkedin.com/in/farkhanhf/ https://github.com/farkhan777

PROFILE SUMMARY

Experience in software engineering, particularly in the field of web backend and frontend. I am a fresh graduate majoring in Informatics from University of Muhammadiyah Malang and have a passion in development and technology such as coding, research, and competitive programming.

EXPERIENCE

Back End Developer - Telkom Indonesia

PT Telekomunikasi Indonesia Tbk

September 2022 - March 2023, Bandung

- Working at National Address Database project to develop, improve, and maintain high quality back-end services and APIs
- Participate in the entire application lifecycle, focusing on coding and debugging
- Working with agile culture
- Within a cross-functional team, collaborate with other developers specializing in backend, frontend, ui/ux, quality assurance, product owner, scrum master, and etc
- Learn multiple tech stacks to use the best tools for the job
- Solve technical problems

Back End Developer - Investree

PT Investree Radhika Jaya

August 2022 - September 2022, Remote

- Learn multiple tech stacks to use the best tools for the job
- Learn database using Postgresql
- Developed REST API by implementing Spring Boot

Back End Engineer - Generasi Gigih 2.0 by YABB & GoTo

Yayasan Anak Bangsa Bisa

February 2022 - July 2022, Remote

- Learn Back End by creating a REST API using Ruby on Rails
- Learn Database using Postgresql, clean code and SOLID principle
- Develope REST API by implementing NodeJs, Sequelize. and Postgresql

Machine Learning and Front-End Web Developer - KAMPUS MERDEKA

PT Presentologics

August 2021 - January 2022, Remote

- Learn Machine Learning and Deep Learning algorithms to create Machine Learning models
- Optimizing Machine Learning Models and deploying models to Flask Framework
- Learn FrontEnd by using ReactJs
- Develope web app by implementing Machine Learning model, Flask, and ReactJs

Laboratory Assistant

Informatics Laboratory UMM

August 2020 - March 2023, Malang

- Helping lecturers explain the material to be delivered to students in accordance with the learning curriculum that has been arranged
- Teaching and assessing the results of practical activities when practicum activities are running
- Coordinate and evaluate student learning outcomes with subject lecturers in practical activities that have been carried out
- Design and write learning modules to support practicum activities with the direction of the course lecturer

EDUCATION BACKGROUND

Bachelor of Computer in Informatics

Minor in Software Engineering · University of Muhammadiyah Malang · Malang · 2019 - 2023

INVOLVEMENT

Member of Information System Division

University of Muhammadiyah Malang, Indonesia · INFOTECH UMM · August 2020 - March 2023

- Perform system maintenance on a regular basis
- Carry out system development according to the needs of the laboratory using several technologies that have been researched previously

SKILLS

Programming Language: Javascript, Typescript, Go, PHP, Java, Python

Database: MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite, MongoDB, Oracle DB

Framework/Library: ReactJs, Laravel, ExpressJs, Restify, Tensorflow, PostGIS, Mocha, JSLint